Register to The Leroy Anderson Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Leroy Anderson Papers
1933-1988
MSS 61
Yale University Music Library
16
(33 boxes)
Music, scrapbooks, and additional materials by and about the American composer Leroy Anderson (1908-1975)
Anderson, Leroy, 1908-1975
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Leroy Anderson Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Eleanor Anderson in 1987.
Arrangement
In 2 series as follows: I. Music. II. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
The Leroy Anderson Papers document Anderson's life and career as a composer chiefly through his music, both published and in manuscript. The Papers also contain scrapbooks and other items.
Biographical / Historical
Leroy Anderson was born on June 29, 1908 in Cambridge, Massachusetts. His family was musical, and as a boy he studied double bass, organ, and trombone. He continued his musical education at Harvard, where his teachers included Walter Piston and Georges Enesco; he graduated from college in 1929, and earned the M.A. in 1930. In the early 1930s he did additional graduate work in Scandinavian languages at Harvard; he also directed the Harvard Band and held numerous other musical jobs.
In 1936 Anderson arranged a medley of Harvard songs for Harvard Night at the Boston Pops. In the ensuing decades, he would become famous largely for the many pieces he composed or arranged for Arthur Fiedler and the Boston Pops, including Jazz Pizzicato (1938), The Syncopated Clock (1945), Sleigh Ride (1948), The Typewriter (1950), and Blue Tango (1951). By the early 1950s, Anderson's music had become extraordinarily popular; his recordings sold in the millions, and American orchestras performed his works more frequently than those of any other American composer.
Anderson later turned several of his most popular orchestral works into songs, with lyrics by Mitchell Parish; of these, Sleigh Ride has had the most lasting success. Anderson also composed a piano concerto (1953), as well as Goldilocks (1958), a Broadway musical with words by Walter and Jean Kerr and Joan Ford.
In 1942 Anderson married Eleanor Jane Firke; they had a daughter and three sons. In 1949 the family settled in Woodbury, Connecticut. Leroy Anderson died in Woodbury on May 18, 1975.
Popular instrumental music; Anderson, Leroy, 1908-1975
- Music, Series I
  - 5 Uhr Tanztee Band 3 Mills Musikverlag et al., c1952; score (27 p.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    published score
    2 voices & piano
    Collection of compositions including Anderson's "Blue Tango." German edition.
  - Add Up, condensed score (6 p.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    holograph
    dance orchestra
    Pencil.
  - Adieu, mein kleiner Gardeoffizier, score (4 p.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    band
  - After All I've Been to You/Hypnotized, 1/10/36; score (6 p.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ah! Sweet Mystery of Life, 1/30/49; condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    orchestra
  - All Wet, condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Pencil. For 1935 Vincent Club show.
  - Alma Mater, 5/31/54; score (37 p.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Penciled additions.
  - Alma Mater Mills Music Inc., c1956; score (32 p.), condensed score (12 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alma Mater Mills Music Inc., c1956; condensed score (12 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alma Mater, score (37 p.) (Box 24, Folder 816)
    Penciled corrections and additions.
  - Alone (A Night at the Opera), 1/2/36; score (4 p.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - An Evening at Home, condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annie Get Your Gun Selections, 1/2/36; condensed score (11 p.) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Irving Berlin
  - Arietta Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (4 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 13)
    string orchestra
  - Arietta Woodbury Music Corporation, score (7 p.) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arietta Woodbury Music Corporation, c1961; score (3 p.) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    piano
  - Arietta Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (10 p.), condensed score (4 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arietta Woodbury Music Corporation, c1961; score (3 p.) (Box 24, Folder 818)
  - Arietta (sketch), condensed score (3 p.) (Box 24, Folder 817)
  - Artist's Life, score (8 p.) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    1937
  - At the End of a Waltz, score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    W.K. Thayer
  - Athletics, condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ave Maria, 2/13/49; condensed score (3 p.) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ave Maria, score (10 p.) (Box 23, Folder 791)
    F. Schubert
    Ink with pencil markings.
    Stamp on page 1: Registered 1949
  - Ave Maria (sketch), condensed score (3 p.) (Box 24, Folder 819)
    violin and orchestra
  - Ay-ay-ay, 5/22/49; condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Balladette Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (5 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Balladette Woodbury Music Corporation, 4/9/62; score (10 p.) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Balladette Woodbury Music Corporation, c1961; score (5 p.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Balladette Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (13 p.), condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Balladette (sketch), condensed score (3 p.) (Box 24, Folder 820)
  - Basin Street Blues, 11/4/40; score (8 p.) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Pencil. "For Ruby Newman."
  - Beautiful Dreamer, 5/15/49; condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Because, 1/2/49; condensed score (2 p.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Begin the Beguine, 2/27/49; condensed score (5 p.) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Begin the Beguine, 12/24/40; score (5 p.) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Cole Porter
  - Begin the Beguine (jubilee), score (4 p.) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1964; score (4 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 32)
    arr. Thomas Tyra
    2 copies.
  - Belle of the Ball, 5/12/51; score (26 p.) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Belle of the Ball, 6/17/59; score (25 p.) & vocal part (Box 1, Folder 34)
    soprano, baritone & orchestra
    Pencil. Includes photocopy of vocal part.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1953; score (7 p.) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    French edition.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1953 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    voice
    vocal part
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 1, Folder 37)
    trumpet & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (7 p.) (Box 1, Folder 38)
    trans. Gerald Crossman
    accordion
    English edition.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (4 p.) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    voice & piano
    3 copies.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (6 p.) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    4 copies.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1952 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    arr. Johnny Warrington
    parts
    English edition. 2 copies.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Ltd., c1954; condensed score (4 p.) & parts (Box 1, Folder 42)
    arr. Ernest Tomlinson
    brass band
  - Belle of the Ball Toa Music Company, c1974 Yomipack Inc.; condensed score (16 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Japanese edition.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    arr. Virginia Carrington Thomas
    organ
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 45)
    violin, cello & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 2, Folder 46)
    violin & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1953; score (5 p.) (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Musikverlag, c1951; score (5 p.) (Box 2, Folder 48)
    German edition.
  - Belle of the Ball, c1965; condensed score (3 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 49)
    arr. Wolfgang Meyer
    VEB Lied Der Zeit
    "Das ist halb so schlimm" on reverse of all parts.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 2, Folder 50)
    alto saxophone & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 2, Folder 51)
    clarinet & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1951; score (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 52)
    2 different printings.
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 53)
    trans. Pietro Deiro
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1955; score (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 54)
    arr. Michael Edwards
    treble voices & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1955; score (12 p.) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    mixed voices & piano
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; condensed score (8 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952; condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Belle of the Ball Mills Music Inc., c1952 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Belle of the Ball, 11/25/51; score (34 p.) (Box 24, Folder 821)
  - Belle of the Ball (Die Ballschöne), c1952; condensed score (2 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 59)
    arr. Bruno Doring
    Edition Meridian
    "Moulin Rouge" on reverse of all parts. German edition.
  - Belle of the Ball (Die Ballschöne), c1952; score (4 p.) (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Belle of the Ball (Die Ballschöne), c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Bruno Schlosser
  - Belle of the Ball (Die Schönste vom Ball), c1952 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    "Fandango" on reverse of all parts. German edition.
  - Belle of the Ball (La Bella del Ballo), c1953; condensed score (4 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 63)
    arr. A. Giacomazzi
    Accordo
    Music for "Il Valzer del Trombettiere" on reverse side of all parts. Italian lyrics by Ardo. Italian edition.
  - Belle of the Ball (sketch), 5/12/51; condensed score (7 p.) (Box 24, Folder 822)
  - Belle of the Ball/Fandango Mills Music Ltd., c1953; score (6 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Parts for "Fandango" on the reverse of "Belle of the Ball." French edition.
  - Bench in the Park, A, score (1 p.) (Box 2, Folder 65)
    male vocal quartet
  - Bert Weedon Guitar Album of Leroy Anderson Favorites - Book I Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (14 p.) (Box 2, Folder 66)
    arr. Bert Weedon
    guitar & bass (or "piano guide")
  - Bert Weedon Guitar Album of Leroy Anderson Favorites - Book II Mills Music Ltd., c1949; score (16 p.) (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Between You and Me, score (7 p.) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    1939
  - Blood Pressure, score (8 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Henry Hardware
  - Blue Danube Waltz, The, 11/6/39; score (8 p.) (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Pencil. "For Richard Himber."
  - Blue September/Somewhere, 10/8/40; score (10 p.) (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1962; score (4 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 73)
    arr. Charles Carter
  - Blue Tango, c1980; score (11 p.) & parts (Box 2, Folder 74)
    arr. James D. Ployhar
    Belwin Mills
  - Blue Tango, score (15 p.) (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Blue Tango, score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 76)
    voice & orchestra
    Pencil. Vocal part lacking and not indicated in score.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (3 p.) & parts plus parts for vocal quartet (Box 3, Folder 77)
    arr. Y. Thomson
    3 copies. French edition.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (2 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 78)
    French edition. 3 copies of score.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (2 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Blue Tango Belwin Mills/Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 81)
    trumpet or cornet & piano
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 82)
    arr. Stanford King
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; parts (9 p.) (Box 3, Folder 83)
    piano four hands
    English edition. 3 copies.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (6 p.) (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 85)
    arr. Pietro Deiro
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 86)
    voice & piano (or ukelele)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    English edition. 4 copies.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1955; condensed score/solo cornet (4 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 89)
    arr. Roger Barsotti
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1953; score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 90)
    arr. Louis Hollingsworth
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1957; score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 91)
    2 copies. Conn registration.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 92)
    3 copies. Hammond registration.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (2 p.) (Box 3, Folder 94)
    Arranged for "simplified piano solo." 2 copies.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Blue Tango, c1981; score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 96)
    arr. Richard Litterst
    handbell choir
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; parts (9 p.) (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Blue Tango, c1965; condensed score (3 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 99)
    arr. Rolf Hurdelhey
    "Deine Blicke können lügen" on reverse of all parts.
  - Blue Tango, c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Blue Tango, c1952; condensed score (4 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 101)
    arr. Ulrich Sommerlatte
  - Blue Tango, c1952; score (2 p.) (Box 3, Folder 102)
    arr. Herwig Peychar
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) & part (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Blue Tango, c1951; score (2 p.) (Box 3, Folder 105)
    mandolin
    Edizioni Curci
    Italian edition. 2 copies.
  - Blue Tango, c1951; condensed score (3 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 106)
    Music for "Vado a Cuba Mambo" on reverse side of all parts. Italian edition.
  - Blue Tango, c1951; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Blue Tango, c1952; score (6 p.) (Box 3, Folder 108)
    voice & piano or piano solo
    J. Albert & Son Pty. Ltd.
    Australian edition.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Ltd., c1952; score (2 p.) (Box 3, Folder 109)
    voice & piano (or ukulele)
    Swedish lyrics by Gösta Rybrant. Swedish edition.
  - Blue Tango World Music Co., c1952; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Blue Tango World Music Co., c1952; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Blue Tango World Music Co., c1952; score (2 p.) (Box 3, Folder 112)
    Dutch lyrics by Jan Remo and Jos. Dams.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1951; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 113)
    published edition
    3 different printings.
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (7 p.) (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; score (9 p.) (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Blue Tango Mills Music Inc., c1952; condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Blue Tango, 10/26/51; score (17 p.) (Box 24, Folder 823)
    Ink.
  - Blue Tango (Der blaue Tango), vocal score (4 p.) (Box 24, Folder 825)
    photocopy of copyist's manuscript
    voice, chorus & piano
    German lyrics by Ralph Maria Siegel.
  - Blue Tango (Sininen Tango) Musiiki Fazer, c1952; score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Blue Tango (sketch), condensed score (4 p.) (Box 24, Folder 824)
  - Blue Tango (Tango Azul) Editora Musical Mills Ltda., c1959; score (5 p.) (Box 3, Folder 120)
    Brazilian edition.
  - Blue Tango (Tango Bleu) World Music Co., score (3 p.) (Box 3, Folder 121)
    French lyrics by Jacques Plante. French edition.
  - Blue Tango/Belle of the Ball, condensed score (4 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 122)
    arr. Bruno Esser
    Music for both compositions on same sheet music. German edition.
  - Blue Tango/Belle of the Ball Mills Musikverlag, c1951; condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 3, Folder 123)
    arr. Herbert Turba
  - Bluebells of Scotland, The, 10/1/61; score (11 p.) (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Bluebells of Scotland, The, score (11 p.) (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Bluebells of Scotland, The Mills Music Inc., c1954; score (5 p.) (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Bluebells of Scotland, The Mills Music Inc., c1962; score (16 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Bluebells of Scotland, The Mills Music Inc., c1962; score (16 p.), condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Brigadoon Selection, 4/27/48; condensed score (15 p.) (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - 'Brigadoon' - Selection, 4/27/48; score (55 p.) (Box 23, Folder 792)
    Frederick Loewe
    Ink with pencil additions
  - Brunoniana, score (1 p.), sketch sheet (2 p.), and program order (Box 4, Folder 130)
    vocal sextet
  - Bugler's Holiday, score (25 p.) (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Bugler's Holiday Belwin Mills /Mills Music Inc., c1954; score (10 p.) & part (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Bugler's Holiday Belwin Mills/Mills Music Inc., c1954; score (10 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 133)
    trumpet trio & piano
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Inc., c1985; score (12 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 134)
    arr. David Baldwin
    brass quintet
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Ltd., c1954; score (10 p.) & part (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Ltd., c1954; part (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Inc., c1964; condensed score (3 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 137)
    arr. Herbert W. Fred
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Ltd., c1954; condensed score (5 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Ltd., c1954; score (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 139)
    Swedish edition.
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Inc., c1954; score (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Inc., c1954; condensed score (8 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Bugler's Holiday Mills Music Inc., c1954; score (8 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 142)
    trans. Michael Edwards
    cornet trio & band
  - Bugler's Holiday (for three trumpets) (sketch), 5/26/54; condensed score (11 p.) (Box 24, Folder 826)
  - Buttons and Bows, condensed score (4 p.) (Box 4, Folder 143)
    Jay Livingston and Ray Anderson
  - Buttons and Bows, score (16 p.) (Box 24, Folder 827)
  - Campaign Song, condensed score (1 p.) (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Captains and the Kings, The Woodbury Music Corporation, c1965; score (47 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Captains and the Kings, The Woodbury Music Corporation, 2/10/65 - c1962; score (22 p.) (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Captains and the Kings, The, 6/16/62; score (22 p.) (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Captains and the Kings, The Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (7 p.) (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Captains and the Kings, The Woodbury Music Corporation, c1965; score (27 p.), condensed score (11 p.) & parts (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Captains and the Kings, The (sketch), 6/16/62; condensed score (6 p.) (Box 24, Folder 828)
  - Carousel Selection, 4/25/46; condensed score (12 p.) (Box 4, Folder 150)
    Richard Rodgers
  - Carousel Waltzes, condensed score (3 p.) (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - 'Carousel' Selection, score (51 p.) (Box 23, Folder 793)
    Ink with pencil and red pencil additions.
  - Chicken Reel, score (33 p.) (Box 5, Folder 152)
    Includes 1 set of photocopies.
  - Chicken Reel Mills Music Inc., c1963; score (28 p.), condensed score (16 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Chicken Reel, 3/19/46; score (33 p.) (Box 24, Folder 829)
  - China Doll Mills Music Ltd., c1951; score (7 p.) (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - China Doll Mills Music Inc., c1951; score (7 p.) (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - China Doll Mills Music Inc., c1953; condensed score (7 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - China Doll Mills Music Inc., c1953; condensed score (6 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - China Doll, 10/18/51; score (28 p.) (Box 24, Folder 830)
  - China Doll (Boneca Chinesa) Editora Musical Mills Ltda., c1959; score (7 p.) (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - China Doll (sketch), condensed score (7 p.) (Box 24, Folder 831)
  - Christmas Day, score (18 p.) (Box 5, Folder 159)
    Gustav Holst
  - Christmas Day Mills Music Inc., c1948; score (7 p.) (Box 5, Folder 160)
    mixed voices & organ or piano
  - Christmas Day (SATB) (sketch), 9/9/47; score (7 p.) (Box 25, Folder 832)
    chorus & organ
  - Christmas Festival (sketch), 6/12/50; condensed score ([13] p.) (Box 23, Folder 794)
    Pencil and red pencil.
  - Christmas Festival, A Mills Music Inc., 6/12/50; photocopied original score (50 p.) & autograph "version for print" score addendum (13 p.) (Box 5, Folder 161)
    autograph holograph/photocopy
    Score addendum in ink with penciled comments and additions.
  - Christmas Festival, A, c1984; score (12 p.) (Box 5, Folder 162)
    arr. Martha Lynn Thompson
  - Christmas Festival, A Mills Music Inc., c1952; condensed score (11 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Christmas Festival, A Mills Music Inc., c1950; condensed score (10 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Christmas Festival, A, 7/23/50; score (37 p.) (Box 25, Folder 833)
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (36 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, 7/21/62; score (36 p.) (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Clarinet Candy, 6/9/62; score (35 p.) (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (11 p.) & part (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (11 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 169)
    2 clarinets & piano
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (11 p.) & parts (Box 5, Folder 170)
    4 clarinets & piano
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1962; score (10 p.) (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Clarinet Candy Woodbury Music Corporation, c1964; score (36 p.), condensed score (12 p.) & parts (Box 6, Folder 172)
  - Clarinet Candy (sketch), 6/9/62; condensed score (9 p.) (Box 25, Folder 834)
  - Class Reunion (Alma Mater) (sketch), 5/31/54; condensed score (7 p.) (Box 25, Folder 835)
  - Classical Jukebox, The, condensed score (6 p.) (Box 6, Folder 173)
  - Come Across (Hasty Pudding Show) Words and Music Inc., c1937; vocal score (33 p.) (Box 25, Folder 836)
    includes program and separately published sheet music for three songs
  - Come Across I, score (3 p.) (Box 6, Folder 174)
    Pencil. For 1937 Hasty Pudding show.
  - Come Across II, score (4 p.) (Box 6, Folder 175)
  - Come On, Let's Add Up the Score, score (1 p.) & lyrics sheet (Box 6, Folder 176)
    Cammann Newberry
    Pencil. For 1935 Hasty Pudding show.
  - Cornell Alma Mater, score (1 p.) (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - Così, Cosa, 2/6/49; condensed score (5 p.) (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Crashing Thru, condensed score (2 p.) (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - Curtain Time - 1948, 4/17/48; condensed score (16 p.) (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Dancing Doll (sketch), condensed score (6 p.) (Box 25, Folder 837)
  - Dancing in the Dark, condensed score and sketches (4 p.) (Box 6, Folder 181)
    male vocal quartet & orchestra
  - Danny Boy, 2/6/49; condensed score (4 p.) (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - Darktown Strutter's Ball, score (5 p.) (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - Donkey Serenade, The, 1/9/49; condensed score (4 p.) (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Don't Tell Miguello, score (6 p.) (Box 6, Folder 184)
    Pencil. For 1936 Hasty Pudding show.
  - Drinking Song, 2/13/49; condensed score (3 p.) (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - Drunk Scene, score (3 p.) (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - East of the Sun, score (1 p.) (Box 6, Folder 188)
    vocal quartet
  - Eire Suite, 5/31/47; score (35, 17, 10, 35 p.) (Box 23, Folder 795)
    Ink with pencil and red and blue pencil additions.